<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Mingxuan Yang</title>
    <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Mingxuan Yang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Creating a SQLite3 Schema Using Spotify Dataset</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/spotify-songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/spotify-songs/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This blog is to create a SQLite3 schema to store Spotify Songs Dataset. This schema should follow the normalization rule to reduce data redundancy and prevent inconsistencies on insertion, update and deletion. Normalization design technique divides large tables into smaller pieces and uses some relationships to connect them. There are many database normal forms, they can be listed from least normalized to most normalized as below:
 UNF: Unnormalized form 1NF: First normal form 2NF: Second normal form 3NF: Third normal form EKNF: Elementary key normal form BCNF: Boyce-Codd normal form 4NF: Fourth normal form ETNF: Essential tuple normal form 5NF: Fifth normal form DKNF: Domain-key normal form 6NF: Sixth normal form  The main normal forms applied in this blog are 1NF, 2NF and 3NF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Malaria Visualization</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/malaria-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/malaria-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Malaria is a fatal disease caused by infected mosquitoes. It has remained with human in a long history and is one of the biggest causes of death. Almost half of the world’s population, according to the World Health Organization (WHO), is at the risk of catching Malaria. To gain more comprehension about this powerful enemy, the Wellcome Trust and Sage Bionetworks have hosted a Data Challenge based on the relevant Malaria datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler Project Problem 85 using Python</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-85/</guid>
      <description>Problem Problem 85: Counting rectangles
By counting carefully it can be seen that a rectangular grid measuring 3 by 2 contains eighteen rectangles:
Although there exists no rectangular grid that contains exactly two million rectangles, find the area of the grid with the nearest solution.
Analysis First of all, we need to specify the number of possible rectangles when the width and length of the grid are x units and y units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler Project Problem 31 using Python</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-31/</guid>
      <description>Problem Problem 31: Coin sums
In the United Kingdom the currency is made up of pound (£) and pence (p). There are eight coins in general circulation: 1p, 2p, 5p, 10p, 20p, 50p, £1 (100p), and £2 (200p). It is possible to make £2 in the following way:
1×£1 + 1×50p + 2×20p + 1×5p + 1×2p + 3×1p
How many different ways can £2 be made using any number of coins?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euler Project Problem 25 using Python</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/euler-project-problem-25/</guid>
      <description>Problem Problem 25: 1000-digit Fibonacci number
The Fibonacci sequence is defined by the recurrence relation:
F(n) = F(n-1) + F(n-2), where F(1) = 1 and F(2) = 1.
Hence the first 12 terms will be:
F(1) = 1
F(2) = 1
F(3) = 2
F(4) = 3
F(5) = 5
F(6) = 8
F(7) = 13
F(8) = 21
F(9) = 34
F(10) = 55
F(11) = 89
F(12) = 144</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Personal Website Using Hugo</title>
      <link>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Mingxuan-Yang.github.io/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Hugo Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators. With the ability of generating most websites within seconds, it provides the users with the world’s fastest framework for building personal websites.
The installation and deployment of Hugo are simple and efficient. With just 7 simple steps, we can easily use Hugo to build our own personal websites. Before introducing the 7 steps, the reader needs to get a Github account.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
